# Gaurav Chaddha

Software Engineer (Android)

chaddhag@gmail.com · (+91) 9006256972 · India · https://gaurav.chaddha.me/

Self-motivated software engineer with experience developing modern android apps for leading companies. Currently shipping new features for Zomato and improving user experience. Increased data transfer rate by 200% at Intugine Tech. A passionate and curious team worker.

#### EXPERIENCE

Zomato Gurugram, India Oct 2018 - Present

Software Engineer

• Ship new features with speed and finesse

- Improve user experience and stability of the consumer app
- In-house debugging tools development

Samsung R&D Institute

Noida, India July 2018 - Oct 2018

Software Engineer

• Restructured and maintained quick tools and yahoo apps

Software Engineer Intern

Jan - May 2018

- Boosted security of apps by providing a security solution for android
- Improved battery life by 40% for Samsung Go platform

# Intugine technologies

Bangalore, India May - June 2017

Software Engineer Intern

- Conceptualized and engineered complete architecture and api of 'Nimble'
- Increased data transfer rate by 200% by subscribing to ble notifications
- Redesigned 'point and control' and 'custom gesture detection' algorithms with 92% accuracy

Witworks Bangalore, India

Software Engineer Intern

May - Jun 2016

- Built core 'Blink' applications like system, dialer and fitness
- Reduced latency by 90% for voice command using bluetooth sco mode

#### SKILLS

- Team player, enthusiastic, positive attitude, hard-working
- Proficient in data structures, problem solving, end-to-end coding, git, security, debugging
- Adept at java, oops, design patterns, generics and java 8
- Skilled in mobile development: android, kotlin, rxjava, dagger, mvp/ mvvm/ mvi patterns, architecture components, material design 2, retrofit, picasso, room, sensor and ble api
- Passionate for system design, functional reactive programming, machine learning, back-end development

## Projects

## Sangeet

A beautiful music player made with material design 2, architecture components, dagger, rxjava and mvi state management

## Rakshak

An end-to-end encrypted email client using imap, smtp with aes and rsa algorithms

#### EDUCATION

# Birla Institute of Technology, Mesra

Ranchi, India 2014 - 2018

Bachelor of Engineering - I.T. GPA: 8.78

- Won 2nd prize representing college at 'Smart India Hackathon'
- Wrote article on dagger with 10k+ views
- Organized and participated in hackathons and capture-the-flag events